Austin Roe 1540 N Fuller Ave Los Angeles, CA 90046

May 20, 2020

Human Resource Representative Rookieplay

I am writing to express my interest in the position posted on Indeed.com's website. I am currently employed with UnitedHealth Group as a Senior Billing Analyst with our Large Employer Group team under E&I Operations.

My background includes over 10 years of leadership, customer service, and team development experience in multiple customer service and healthcare environments. I studied Nursing and Business Management at Itasca Community College and Hibbing Community College where I discovered my passion for a career in the Healthcare Industry.

I am currently employed with United Health Group as a Senior Billing Analyst within our E&I Operations team. In this role, I am accountable for the payment integrity and processing of hundreds of Employer Group premiums payments as well as their associated fees and state-specific taxes, as well as with proactive and reciprocal communication with both the HR, Senior Leadership, Accounts Receivable, and Accounts Payable representatives both within my designated employer groups and UnitedHealthcare as a whole. I often divide my time between self-driven, independently managed work, working as a team with my internal business partners to reach a resolution for a complex issue or with my team as a peer coach and assistant and assisting with special projects related to the business.

I believe the most important strength one can have is a strong focus on team culture and positive employee & client engagement. Agents who focus on developing a strong and sustainable core culture focused on their team's success help flourish the evolution and innovations of great teams and businesses. Through culture focus and positive leadership, I have proven my performance in this organization and to my team throughout my career.

I am looking forward to discussing the position and my qualifications with you in more detail soon. Feel free to contact me by email at austinroe218@gmail.com and by phone at (218) 393-1386.

Sincerely,

Austin G. Roe

Austin Roe

Address: 1540 N Fuller Ave Los Angeles, CA 90046

Email: austinroe218@gmail.com Phone Number: 218-393-1386

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Sr. Billing Analyst

UnitedHealthcare 4316 Rice Lake Rd Duluth, MN 55711 11/25/2019 – Present

Description: Senior Billing Analyst trained in large-dollar premium allocation, account reconciliation, delinquent escalation, triaging and resolving client concerns and inquiries relating to billing package and invoices, working with team and internal business partners for assistance with or redirection of out of scope issues, peer coaching and assistance.

Elite Advocate

UnitedHealthcare 4316 Rice Lake Rd Duluth, MN 55711 08/05/2018 – 11/24/2019

Description: Dedicated Member Services representative trained in Answering Claims Processing, Medical, Mental Health, Pharmacy, Gender Re-Assignment Benefits, and Claims inquiries. Triaging and resolving complex and escalated issues for customers while working with our Internal Business Partners to work towards the best scenario for all parties Involved. AC2E Coach Certified (Internal on-the-job trainer program designed to educate and train designated employees for potential future leadership opportunities and positions within the company.)

Advocate4Me Rep

UnitedHealthcare 4316 Rice Lake Rd Duluth, MN 55711 06/19/2017 – 08/05/2018

Description: Member Services representative trained in Answering Claims & Benefit questions and triaging and routing more complex issues to appropriate teams. Internal Commitment Inventory Report trained, where-in Agent would review co-workers routed

issues for errors and re-route or resolve issues and send educational emails to original representative as appropriate.

Staff Member

Son Group LLC - Cloquet, MN - September 2016 – 06/16/2017

Description: Correlating with a direct line of professionals to implement new procedures, insure quality of products, and provide service in a safe and effective manner.

Customer Service Specialist

New Directions Senior Living LLC - Cloquet, MN - July 2016 — September 2016 **Description:** Managing and directing the Healthcare directives of on-site residents, as well as overseeing the implementation of new procedures, and ensuring quality of service delivered.

Health Care Specialist

Guardian Angels Health & Rehabilitation LLC - Hibbing, MN - October 2015 – June 2016 **Description:** Managing and directing the Healthcare directives of on-site residents, as well as overseeing the implementation of new procedures, and ensuring quality of service delivered.

Nursing Assistant Registered

Welcov Healthcare - Grand Rapids, MN - August 2015 — October 2015 **Description:** Daily & Personal Cares for Disabled Adults.

Health Care Specialist/Hospitality & Beverage Manager

Whispering Pines Assisted Living & Memory Care, LLC - Grand Rapids, MN - June 2015 – September 2015

Description: Monitor, limit, and recording intake. Overseeing daily preparation of onsite meals, and housekeeping. Cataloging, inventory, and distribution of medication and controlled substances to on-site residents. Helped to coordinate with staff to solve day to day, and persisting problems. Also worked one on one with residents to access needs and desires.

Nursing Assistant Registered

Welcov Healthcare, LLC Grand Rapids, MN - February 2015 — May 2015 **Description**: Daily & Personal Cares for Disabled Adults.

Health and Sanitation Operator

Ground Round - Grand Rapids, MN - September 2014 - February 2015

Description: Overseeing proper implementation of sanitary procedures and Health Code observance. Orientation and training of new employees. Inventory and ordering.

Customer Service Manager

CLK Management Co, LIC - Grand Rapids, MN . July 2013 - July 2014

Description: Directly responsible for Health Code and Product Safety procedures and observances. Orientation and Training of new employees. Teaching and implementing new procedures to staff members. Responsible for raising and maintaining company morale. Directing staff, and company activity throughout peak activity and daily occurrences.

Customer Service Manager

Phaneuf Co, LLC - Hibbing, MN - August 2011 - July 2013

Description: Directly responsible for Health Code and Product Safety procedures and observances. Orientation and Training of new employees. Teaching and implementing new procedures to staff members. Responsible for raising and maintaining company morale.

Customer Service Manager

Yannis Original Gyros - Hibbing, MN - August 2008 - August 2011

Description: Directly responsible for Health Code and Product Safety procedures and observances. Orientation and Training of new employees. Teaching and implementing new procedures to staff members. Responsible for raising and maintaining company morale.

EDUCATION:

- Nursing Aid Certification in Nursing Itasca Community College - Grand Rapids, MN August 2014 – March 2015
- Business Management/Computer Science Hibbing Community College – Hibbing, MN August 2012 – June 2013

SKILLS:

Types 100 WPM (13+ years). Microsoft Office Fluent (8 years), Customer Relationship Management (10 years), On-the-Job Coaching (10 years).

Recognition

Across my career at UnitedHealthcare, currently spanning almost two and a half years, I've received a number of outstanding feedback from my co-workers and other Internal Business Partners. Some of the most impactful feedback is listed below:

AUSTIN ROE

has received recognition from MICHELLE FELLBAUM for Performance

Helping Hand

Austin thank you for all of your continued support with the Elite team, I appreciate every time you take some time out of what you are doing to respond to a team member if there is a question that is left unanswered, you are always thorough with your research, and can provide the steps you have taken to get the answer. You have truly made an impact on my knowledge with this job, thank you!

1.

AUSTIN ROE

has received recognition from LARRY KNOX for Performance

Follow Through

Austin has shown with hard work and perseverance you can accomplish anything. Kudos to Austin to grabbing a hold of his commitments from double digit numbers and down to a zero. way to go you are truly a Elite Agent!

2.

AUSTIN ROE

has received recognition from LARRY KNOX for Performance

Austin Always Excels

Austin has been the go to person for out Of Scope issues that can not be resolved. There has been a issue that has been getting routed around for over a month. Austin took charge and resolved the issue in hour and reprocessed claims associated with it. Thank you Austin this does not go unnoticed.

3.

AUSTIN ROE

has received recognition from SHAUNA STROUD for Performance

Thank You Austin!

Austin assisted in a highly complicated, escalated issue and was able to resolve the matter within a few hours. The claim had been routed over 20 times with no resolution. Multiple supervisors from different departments had been involved and every time, the issue fell through the cracks in our systems. I reached out to Austin for help. He willing gave his time, energy and knowledge and was able to finally resolve the issue for our member.

4.

AUSTIN ROE

has received recognition from NIKKOL MONIOT for Relationships

True Leader

Austin is always so helpful when it comes to answering questions, knowing where to find an answer, and going above and beyond when it comes to helping members, and team members. I had a difficult claim issue, and he took over and helped get it taken care of in a very timely manner, and called our member back to give her the good news. Thank you for always being there for our members and our teams. You are very much appreciated for all that you do.

5.

AUSTIN ROE

has received recognition from AMANDA JAMES for Collaboration

Thank you

Thank you so much Austin for all of your help. Not just with the processing but with the computer issues, macro issues, lost links and of course the reference sheets you make. You help all of us in so many ways. Your teamwork skills are truly amazing! I am so thankful to be working with you now, and going forward.

6.

AUSTIN ROE

has received recognition from DEBORAH JORGE for Collaboration

Your Feedback Helps Improve Advocate Experience

Thank you so much, Austin, for your ongoing support and feedback on our benefit search capability and Benefit Eligibility and Coverage Hub (BEACH) UI. On behalf of the entire team, we thank you for your proactive outreach, insightful feedback and commitment to helping us enhance benefit content management and search capabilities for our users. Your input allows us to create an intuitive and user-friendly online experience for advocates and clinicians who serve our members, providers and other constituents. Moreover, it helps drive simplicity and health literacy, which influences the appropriate utilization of benefits and contributes to a higher Net Promoter Score. Your partnership means the world to us. Thank you, thank you, thank you.

7.

AUSTIN ROE

has received recognition from MICHELLE WORACHEK for Collaboration

Thank you Austin!

Austin, thank you for the great detail you provided regarding the quick list when routing ORS. This issue has been reported as a system defect #ICN7915791. The support you provide will allow us to reduce the amount of inappropriate routes and expedite our member issues.

AUSTIN ROE

has received recognition from RACHEL MALZAHN for Collaboration

BEElieve!

Austin is always there to help his teammates in the team chat and supporting them when questions arise. He supports collaboration and open communication within the team to assure everyone is successful!

9. _ ...

References

- Micky Follansbee Provider Relations Supervisor 715-919-3086 or 218-279-5786
 Known for 3 years.
- 2. Larry Knox Elite Super Advocate 800-797-9978 ext. 52680 Known for 3 years.
- 3. Thomas Bullert Elite Advocate 218-224-3755 Known for 2 year.